Sunil Kumar

sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +1-6043674432 linkedin.com/in/sunilkumarsheoran ECS 412, University of Victoria, Victoria, BC, Canada. V8P 5C2

I am a Master of Computer Science student at the University of Victoria. I have 3 years of software development experience with software product companies. I am seeking co-op opportunities where I can fully utilize my skills for the success of the organization and learn new skills for the cutting edge of technologies in the industry.

Education

M.Sc. in Computer Science Jan 2019 - Expected Dec 2020 University of Victoria, BC, Canada. - 7.33 / 9.0 GPA

Projects: Training a DQN agent for Coinrun (github.com/Unimax/coinrun-dqn-pytorch) and Matchmaking for online multiplayer games (git.io/JenE4).

B.Tech. in Information Technology Aug 2010-May 2014 NIT Durgapur, West Bengal, India. - 8.10 / 10.0 CGPA Projects: Collage Study Point Website (git.io/JenEB), Digital Clock on Multisim and Exploration bot.

Technical Skills

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, Golang, PostgreSQL, MySQL, C, C++, PHP, CSS, HTML.
- Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Office, Adobe Photoshop, gRPC, REST APIs, Git, Google Web Toolkit (GWT), JDBC, Hibernate, OOPs, Data Structures, Deep Learning, Electron, Angular, Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF), Jasper Report.
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

Experience

Technical Associate / Zillious Solutions, New Delhi, India.

July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Developed an alternative for Java enum reaching its limit issue, causing minimum changes in the application.
- Incorporated support for customizable vouchers and integrated multiple payment gateways including *PayTM*, *Razerpay*, etc.
- Integrated pre-developed machine learning model into the application for finding duplicate hotels.

Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram, India.

June 2014 – Sep 2016

- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014 (i.e. 10 days 24x7 coding event).
- Majorly worked on Ameyo Report, a GWT based front-end, and Jasper based backend; This includes a UI renew, automating the generation of *Transformers*, a data de-normalization component, by using EMF modeling and backend enhancements.
- Created a report scheduler based on the Quartz library with support for centralized reporting and graphical reports.
- Increased performance for a large customer's reporting database by 90% using table partition and multicolumn indexes.
- Increased performance of a statics managing component by 60% using soft references based cache for reflective calls.
- Developed a context-aware report designer with the Front-end based on GWT with data populating based on EMF model instances and outputs a proprietary file format (.drxml) which converted by the backend into a jasper-reports based object. It was used to give demos to international customers as a future project.
- Created Magic Numbers: Predicts hardware requirements (CPU, RAM, and HDD) based on customer functional requirements.
- Delivered components for the automation of the collection process for HDFC (Indian Bank). Implemented a fresh UI, Integrating
 Hitachi Content Platform (HCP) for report storage, SSO Authentication server & various domain-specific features like
 Centralized Exclusion.
- Part of the Hiring team for the 2016 and 2017 hiring seasons. Prepared questions, Interviewed candidates and did the training after hiring.

Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore, India.

June 2013 - Aug 2013

• Designed and developed the front-end interface for a research project called 'Development of A Flexible Framework for A Network On Chip'. We wrote a research paper about it (git.io/Jen9I).

Personal Interests

- Video Games: Won 2nd place in COBX and Aorus Land 2017 National DOTA 2 tournaments, 1st place in Playtonia Delhi and Indian LAN Gaming Cup Delhi DOTA 2 tournaments.
- Karate: Green belt in Shūkōkai Karate.
- Solving Programming Problems: Won 1st place in *Behind the Scene* 2013, 1st place in *InCanity* 2013 and 2nd place in Simplex 2012.
- Playing Chess: 3rd, 1st and 2nd place in Regional Sports Meet in 2007, 2006 and 2005. Won a place in K.V. National Sports Meet.

References

- Sahil Gandhi (sahilgandhi2011@gmail.com) Product Evangelist, Ameyo (previously known as Drishti-Soft Solutions).
- **Dr. Hausi Müller** (<u>hausi@uvic.ca</u>) Professor, University of Victoria.